Joseph Knox

650.709.7272 | joseph.edward.knox@gmail.com | Github: jknox13 | LinkedIn: Joseph Knox

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

M.S. IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS June 2018 | Seattle, WA

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

B.S. IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING Minor in Applied Mathematics June 2016 | Seattle, WA

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

Languages: Python •C • Java •R

ML libs: SkLearn • XGBoost • PyTorch
DB (SQL): Presto • Hive • MySQL • Spark
Systems: Linux (Arch, CentOS) • Docker

OPEN SOURCE

MCMODELS | MAINTAINER

2017 - 2018 | Python

Python library for mesoscopic full-brain connectivity models in mouse – built on top of the AllenSDK and Scikit-Learn APIs.

RISTRETTO | PRIMARY CONTRIBUTOR

2018 | Python

Randomized matrix factorization library written in Python (numpy).

CONTRIBUTER TO

- Allensdk
- Scikit-learn

COURSEWORK

GRADUATE

Statistical Computing Combinatorial Optimization Computational Neuroscience Statistical Analysis of Social Networks Computational Methods - Data Analysis

UNDERGRADUATE

Machine Learning Stochastic Modeling/Decision Analysis Linear and Network Programming High-Performance Scientific Computing

SUMMARY

I am a Data Scientist with 3+ years of experience driving business impact through research, analytics, and engineering. Throughout my diverse work experience, I have identified, communicated, and solved various levels of problems with close collaboration with cross-functional partners. The problems I'm most interested in working on problems require industry-leading solutions to solve: solutions that bridge the gap between research and production code.

EXPERIENCE

FACEBOOK

DATA SCIENTIST

Sept 2018 - Present • 1 yr 8 mos

San Francisco, CA

- Own analytic strategy focused on Instagram SMB advertiser value
- Identify product gaps and market opportunities, working with many cross-functional partners to influence product and marketing roadmaps
- Build end-to-end ML models to predict advertiser churn and retention lift
- Build and contribute to internal tools streamlining data visualization, ML modeling, and experimentation measurement
- Write data pipelines to support analysis, internal tools, and external personalized marketing campaigns

ALLEN INSTITUTE FOR BRAIN SCIENCE

DATA ANALYST

June 2017 - Sept 2018 · 1 yr 4 mos

Seattle, WA

- Develop and implement novel models for full-brain connectivity
- Analyze heterogeneous, multi-scale experimental data
- Contribute to organizational open source software packages
- Research statistical, graph theoretic models of brain connectivity

RATLAB LLC

RESEARCH INTERN

July 2016 – Jan 2017 · 7 mos

Seattle, WA

- Designed and conducted experiments for product R&D
- Optimized hardware design through the use of statistical ML techniques

COLLEGE WORKS PAINTING

Manager

Feb 2015 - Sept 2015 · 8 mos

Seattle, WA

- Acted as project manager sourcing clients and creating estimates for management of monetary funds
- Planned production schedule and successfully coordinated all projects, interacting with clients daily and ensured customer satisfaction
- Recruited, hired, and trained 3 employees

SELECT PUBLICATIONS

- [1] J. A. Harris, S. Mihalas, et al. Hierarchical organization of cortical and thalamic connectivity. *Nature*, 575(7781):195–202, 2019.
- [2] J. E. Knox, K. D. Harris, et al. High-resolution data-driven model of the mouse connectome. *Network Neuroscience*, 3(1):217–236, 2019.
- [3] J. D. Whitesell et al. Whole brain imaging reveals distinct spatial patterns of amyloid beta deposition in three mouse models of alzheimer's disease. *Journal of Comparative Neurology*, 527(13):2122–2145, 2019.